WILLIAM S. GRIFFITH IV

6930 Providence Square Dr. Charlotte, NC 28270 wsgriffithiv@gmail.com 828.320.7174

behance.net/wsg4

SUMMARY

Content manager with over twelve years of experience curating online content and adapting to new social media trends to engage our audience. Key strengths include digital and print content creation, client-facing relations, and cross-departmental team management. Excellent leadership, organization, and communication skills, with special experience public speaking and event planning.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DIOCESE OF CHARLOTTE

DIGITAL CONTENT MANAGER

Charlotte, NC

- Worked with WebDev to develop and deploy four different websites for the Diocese of Charlotte.
 Sites curated include:
 - o The Diocese of Charlotte: charlottediocese.org
 - o The Year of Mercy: <u>yearofmercy.rcdoc.org</u>
 - o The Eucharistic Congress: goeucharist.com
 - o The Year of St. Joseph: yearofstjoseph.org
- Use WordPress to update the Diocesan website and manage the digital content of ten different departments in the Education Vicariate.
- Use GravityView and Excel to interpret data for driving attendance to conferences and events.
 Evaluate key demographics, event timing, and event locations to improve attendance over three years.
- Quality-analysis on Diocesan web page and additional subdomains to test front-end and back-end themes, libraries, and additional code. This includes working with the WebDev to develop childthemes in Wordpress and manipulating CSS to achieve a well-designed user-experience for website visitors.
- Create advertising collaterals, flyers, and registration forms using Adobe Illustrator, InDesign, and Photoshop to market events hosted by the Diocese.

DIOCESE OF CHARLOTTE July 2017-Present

ASHEVILLE-CENTRAL REGIONAL COORDINATOR

Charlotte, NC

The Asheville-Central Regional Coordinator for the Office of Faith Formation acts as the liaison between the Diocesan offices and the branches of the region, providing communication, support, and programs to assist regional parishes in their religious formation curricula.

 Pursue, plan, and coordinate regular meetings with parish program leaders from over 30 different branches in the Asheville and Piedmont region of Western North Carolina to provide a resource for updates on Diocesan-wide events, teaching programs, and policies. Support the Director of Faith Formation in planning Diocesan-wide events that provide opportunities
for continuing education and faith development, including bimonthly symposiums and annual
conferences that reach up to 20,000 members.

DIOCESE OF CHARLOTTE August 2016-July 2017

EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT TO THE EDUCATION OFFICE

Charlotte, NC

The Faith Formation Office provides educational programming and events, which offer opportunities for continuing education and faith enrichment.

- Acted as liaison between Education Vicariate and the IT Department for web development projects, including a Diocesan-wide website redesign and launching separately designed subdomains for temporary websites.
- Managed event planning for various Diocesan activities and launched new electronic platforms for online registrations.
- Successfully catalogued a media library of over 3,000 items, including books, DVDs, and VHS tapes, and updated card-catalogue a digital platform.

ST. ALOYSIUS CHURCH July 2007-August 2015

DIRECTOR OF YOUTH MINISTRY

Hickory, NC

- Planned and implemented curricular programs for faith and moral development in local youth, which
 included budget and event management for a parish that reached over 60 teens consistently.
- Planned and hosted annual weekend retreats for teens and adults that included formational opportunities,
 team-building activities, lodging, meals, and gifts for attendees.
- Managed a group of adult volunteers and regularly provided team-building opportunities with group, including book clubs, retreats, and social events.
- Planned fundraising opportunities for the youth that raised \$10,000/year to support mission trips, retreats, summer camps, and other various youth activities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Windows OS

Microsoft Office

Adobe CS/CC (Ps, Ai, Id, Pr)

Content Management Systems (Wordpress, Joomla, WildApricot)

Sublime Text

HTML/CSS

Public Speaking

Event Management

EDUCATION

Franciscan University of Steubenville

Steubenville, OH

Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy & Theology

Minor in History